export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. ...... refers to the structure of a work of art.",
A: "form",
B: "Plot",
C: "Setting",
D: "Style",
answer: "A. form",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Conflict in a literary work begins to unfold with",
A: "climax",
B: "episode",
C: "exposition",
D: "resolution",
answer: "C. exposition",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The character assumed by the author in his writing is",
A: "protagonist",
B: "chorus",
C: "persona",
D: "pseudonym",
answer: "C. persona",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Oral literature is part of",
A: "drama",
B: "folklore",
C: "poetry",
D: "music",
answer: "B. folklore",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Poetry is written in",
A: "chapters",
B: "paragraphs",
C: "scenes",
D: "lines",
answer: "D. lines",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Poetry is written in",
A: "descriptive",
B: "dramatic",
C: "narrative",
D: "poetic",
answer: "D. poetic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The ....... produces comic relief in drama",
A: "chorus",
B: "protagonist",
C: "antagonist",
D: "clown",
answer: "D. clown",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A short play is also called a",
A: "farce",
B: "novelette",
C: "playlet",
D: "slapstick",
answer: "C. playlet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The rhyme scheme is",
A: "abab",
B: "aaba",
C: "abcc",
D: "abbc",
answer: "A. abab",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The lines are iambic",
A: "pentameter",
B: "trimeter",
C: "tetrameter",
D: "hexameter",
answer: "A. pentameter",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The lines constitute",
A: "an epic",
B: "a quatrain",
C: "an ode",
D: "a sestet",
answer: "B. quatrain",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. ''The sun smiled gently on the scene'' illustrates",
A: "paradox",
B: "euphemism",
C: "hyperbole",
D: "personification",
answer: "C. metaphor",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The major part of the Petrarch sonnet is the",
A: "quintet",
B: "sestet",
C: "tercet",
D: "octave",
answer: "D. octave",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A Poem that celebrates an object, person or event is",
A: "a sonnet",
B: "a dirge",
C: "an ode",
D: "a balled",
answer: "C. an ode",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. ''That it will rain is not unlike'' illustrates the use of",
A: "irony",
B: "lilotes",
C: "metaphor",
D: "metonymy",
answer: "B. lilotes (understatement)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An...... is an indirect and usually unfavourable remark",
A: "allusion",
B: "irony",
C: "aside",
D: "innuendo",
answer: "D. innuendo",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. 'Many hands make light work' illustrates the use of",
A: "zeugma",
B: "hyperbole",
C: "metonymy",
D: "synecdoche",
answer: "D. synecdoche ('hands' representing the people)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Through ........ the ills of society are criticised with the objective of having them corrected",
A: "dramatic irony",
B: "comic relief",
C: "satire",
D: "farce",
answer: "C. satire",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The dominant device used in the lines is",
A: "simile",
B: "alliteration",
C: "assonance",
D: "personification",
answer: "D. personification",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The picture presented is one of",
A: "quiet sea",
B: "dark sky",
C: "stormy weather",
D: "calm season",
answer: "C. stormy weather",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The attitude of the writer towards the President is one of",
A: "contempt",
B: "disdain",
C: "disinterest",
D: "approval",
answer: "D. approval (The description is full of warmth and appreciation for the couple's simple life)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The prevailing atmosphere is",
A: "tense",
B: "sad",
C: "cordial",
D: "warm",
answer: "B. personification. (The pot 'willingly kept company,' the logs 'burned themselves out')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The expression ''plastered on each of their face like a death mask'' illustrates.",
A: "alliteration and metaphor",
B: "simile and personification",
C: "personification and alliteration",
D: "metaphor and simile",
answer: "C. security of the hut.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. ''......... screaming anger'' is an example of",
A: "allusion",
B: "personjfication",
C: "simile",
D: "euphei,,,,,ism",
answer: "B. pun. ('rude room of such a poor pair')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The last paragraph illustrates",
A: "foreshadow",
B: "pathos",
C: "bathos",
D: "climax",
answer: "D. night. (Emphasis on keeping out the cold night air)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The theme of the poem is",
A: "indecision",
B: "separation",
C: "rejected love",
D: "requited love",
answer: "B. abab abab aabb.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The speaker is",
A: "decisive",
B: "frustrated",
C: "disappointed",
D: "angry",
answer: "B. invoking the spirit of womanhood.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The dominant literary device used in the poem is",
A: "paradox",
B: "parody",
C: "metaphor",
D: "oxymoron",
answer: "B. personification. ('God cause to shine on you His face')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The mood of the poem is",
A: "jubilant",
B: "sad",
C: "gloomy",
D: "romantic",
answer: "B. joy.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The poem can be described as",
A: "an epitaph",
B: "a lyric",
C: "a lullaby",
D: "an elegy",
answer: "C. inversion. ('bring forth' instead of 'bring to birth')",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The speaker is",
A: "Othello",
B: "Duke",
C: "Brabantio",
D: "lago",
answer: "A. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The speaker is addressing",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Brabantio",
C: "Roderigo",
D: "Othello",
answer: "A. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. ''Sooty bosom'' is a metaphor for",
A: "a black coat",
B: "Othello",
C: "a breastplate",
D: "lago",
answer: "B. Hamlet.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. ''Run from her guardege'' refers to",
A: "Emilia",
B: "Desdemona",
C: "Bianca",
D: "Cassio's mistress",
answer: "D. anxious.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The setting is",
A: "another street outside the Sagittary",
B: "a council chamber",
C: "a seaport in Cyprus",
D: "the citadel",
answer: "C. strength and size.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker is",
A: "Brabantio",
B: "Cassio",
C: "Gratiano",
D: "lago",
answer: "B. Marcellus.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The addressee is",
A: "Othello",
B: "Duke",
C: "Roderigo",
D: "Montano",
answer: "A. Bernado.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. What has happened to the speaker?",
A: "He has been fined",
B: "He has fallen out of favour",
C: "He has been denied promotion",
D: "He has lost his job",
answer: "B. ghost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The underlined expression shows that the speaker is",
A: "jovial",
B: "insincere",
C: "polite",
D: "unfriendly",
answer: "A. frightening.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The setting is",
A: "a street in Venice",
B: "a street in Cyprus",
C: "outside the citadel",
D: "a court before the citadel",
answer: "B. a platform in front of the castle.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The speaker is addressing",
A: "Cassio",
B: "Duke",
C: "herself",
D: "himself",
answer: "D. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The speaker is",
A: "Othello",
B: "lago",
C: "Lodovico",
D: "Bianca",
answer: "A. exits.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Just before this speech,",
A: "Othello falls into a trance",
B: "Bianca flings a handkerchief at Cassio",
C: "Montano fights with Cassio",
D: "Roderigo is killed",
answer: "D. Ophelia.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. ''medicine'' in the extract refers to the speaker's",
A: "hatred",
B: "passion",
C: "lies",
D: "loyalty",
answer: "C. Polonius.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The character that enters immediately after is",
A: "lago",
B: "Emilia",
C: "Othello",
D: "Cassio",
answer: "A. loyal madness. (Polonius hopes Ophelia's beauty will distract Hamlet from his melancholy)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The speaker is",
A: "Bianca",
B: "Emilia",
C: "Clown",
D: "Desdemona",
answer: "B. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The characters that just left the scene are",
A: "Othello and lago",
B: "Montano and Cassio",
C: "Othello and Desdemona",
D: "Grantiano and Desdemona",
answer: "A. Horatio.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. 'She' in the extract refers to",
A: "Bianca",
B: "Desdemona",
C: "Emilia",
D: "Musician",
answer: "D. dead bodies.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. 'My wayward husband' refers to",
A: "Othello",
B: "lago",
C: "Cassio",
D: "Roderigo",
answer: "C. Hamlet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. In the extract ''this napkin'' is ''the token'' of love between",
A: "lago and Emilia",
B: "Cassio and Desdemona",
C: "Bianca and Cassio",
D: "Desdemona and Othello",
answer: "D. Laertes and the king.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]